Jorge Castaño

TECH LEAD FRONT END DEVELOPER

- (+34) 619 54 03 55
- hola@jorge-castano.com
- Madrid, Spain
- LinkedIn <u>Jorge Castaño</u>
- http://jorge-castano.com/

ABOUT ME

I am a Senior Front End Engineer — currently also a **Tech Lead**.

I have worked in many different JavaScript projects such as fintech, banks, health care, automobile & videogames, for start-ups and top tech companies.

Now I am a ReactJS enthusiast, but I have also professional development experience with Angular (5[†]), VueJS, React Native and Backbone.

TOP SKILLS

90 %

JavaScript

90%

HTML5 & CSS3 (SASS)

85%

React JS

80%

Angular

95%

Public Speaking

LANGUAGES

Spanish - Native English – B2 TOEIC Certificate

German – B2 Goethe Zertifikat

EDUCATION

MSc. Telecom Engineer

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid 2014

Master Thesis

RWTH Aachen, Germany 2013 - 2014

EXPERIENCE

Tech Lead - Senior Front End Developer

Daimler

2019 - Present

Tech Lead and Senior Front End developer. Created many projects from draft to deployment for Mercedes-Benz and Daimler AG.

- Front End Architecture & Development with ReactJS.
- Front End Tech Lead in many projects.
- Mentorship for junior developers, Code reviews & pair programming.

Front End Developer

Minsait (indra)

2017 - 2019

Front End development for BBVA, Bankinter, Santalucía, and Pull & Bear (Inditex).

- Front End Architecture & Development with Angular, Backbone & Vue.
- Code reviews and development design.
- Unit Testing with TapeJS & E2E Testing with Selenium.

Mobile & Front End Developer

Aslam, New IT

2015 - 2017

Mobile & Front end development for PSA Peugeot Citroën and Capgemini.

- Hybrid mobile apps: Cordova, Backbone & Marionette
- Front End: HTML, CSS & JavaScript. Ajax + REST Services.

Fullstack Developer

Krama, e-Soft

2014 - 2015

Front and Back End development for Canal +, Banco popular and AtlCapital.

- FullStack Technologies: JavaScript + jQuery, HTML, CSS, Java, Struts, JSP.
- Hybrid mobile apps: Cordova, IBM MobileFirst, Android.